# Will Morcombe

07859820468

in

/in/will-morcombe-bb59411a3/

wtmorco@live.co.uk

github.com/willmorcombe

Maple Lodge, Sandy Lane, Woodbridge, Suffolk, IP12 4DW

# **PROFILE**

A cheerful and enthusiastic recent masters graduate in Advanced Computer Science, that is charged by a constant desire to learn and innovate (and some good coffee)! Through university experiences I've been exposed to several technology stacks and methodologies that have helped me grasp a deeper understanding to how software is produced. My passion for technology and computer science delves deeper than just my university experiences. Long term interests in technology blogs, especially in machine learning, such as the OpenAI blog, the DeepMind blog, and the YouTube channel, two-minute papers are constantly examined to keep me up to date with the growth and advances in technology.

#### **EDUCATION**

o 2020-2021 – Advanced Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence – MSc

Achieved a Distinction (75%).

University of Leeds.

o 2017-2020 - Computer Science - BSc

Achieved a First-Class Honours (81%).

De Montfort University.

o 2009-2016 – A-Levels and GCSEs

Completed three A-Levels, one AS-Level, and ten GCSEs to a high level.

Woodbridge School, Suffolk.

## **TECHNOLOGY SKILLS**

#### Programming languages that I am proficient in:

Python, Java, JavaScript, SQL, and MongoDB.

#### Programming languages that I am familiar with:

C#, Scala, HTML/CSS, and PHP.

Very familiar with object-oriented design due to many university assignments having to be designed in this manner and achieved 74% in an advanced software engineering module. This ranged from fundamentals of OO, for example looking at the SOLID principles in a practical manor, to exploring the different software architecture styles for different companies circumstances.

A strong understanding of the agile manifesto and its implications has been ingrained into me over my past four years in higher education. This is because every group assignment needed to be completed using the agile beliefs as this would help prepare us for industry work.

# UNIVERSITY AND SIDE PROJECTS

**Offline handwriting recognition:** Built in python, this was used as an introduction to artificial intelligence as a neural network was built from scratch only using helper libraries such as NumPy and Matplotlib. The final product was used for translating study notes into online documents with the added benefit of learning the basics of machine learning.

**Early classification of sepsis from medical data:** Also, built-in python, using actual ICU patient data from two different hospitals, an investigation was carried out to determine whether sepsis onset could be predicted by a patient's vitals and laboratory values. Logistic regression, data imputation and manipulation techniques were used, taking advantage of libraries such as Pandas and PyTorch.

**Tetris bot:** This was created as a fun side project to try and get an AI model to endlessly play Tetris. It used a pre-existing game of Tetris from tetris.com and was built in python.

**Sorting algorithm visualization:** A small but fun side project of visualizing certain sorting algorithms.

**Maze generator:** Another small visualization of a maze generator using the backtracking algorithm created in Java.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Golf and hospitality assistant – Leicester golf center.

June 2019 to December 2019

- Needed to be pro-active and organized as I was on shift alone most of the time and many important jobs were left for me to complete (stock organisation and checking).
- o Established crucial customer service relationships which were a key aspect of the job.

Front of House Staff - Ye Olde Bell and Steelyard.

August 2016 to March 2018

• A combination of leadership qualities and communication skills obtained from training new staff, running the bar, and organizing stock checks.

#### **INTERESTS**

One of my main interests if not self-evident from my personal projects is the current state of artificial intelligence and the new technologies that are being created with the use of it. My other main hobby is golf, playing off a handicap of four, I have competed and led my county's junior team victories even on a national scale. I love getting out and travelling the country finding beautiful golf courses to enjoy!

References are available upon request. Thanks for taking the time to read this far down my CV!